你没有可依靠的人  对吗
You have no one at all, right?
我的丈夫
My husband.
八个月前他在阿富汗牺牲了
He died in Afghanistan eight months ago.
-小卡  -你好  迪恩
- Cass. - Hello, Dean.
把我带出炼狱不是你的责任
Getting me out of purgatory wasn't your responsibility.
我挣脱开的  我需要苦行赎罪
I pulled away. I needed to do penance.
为了我在天堂和人间犯下那么多罪孽
For the things I did on earth and in heaven.
你到底是怎么出来的
How...the hell did you make it out?
我叫娜奥米  我们救了你
My name is Naomi. We rescued you.
我们的对话就算是你的报答
Consider these chats your repayment.
你要定期向我汇报
You will report in to me regularly,
但是你永远不会记得你这么做过
and you will never remember having done so.
如今
俄克拉荷马州  俄克拉荷马市
盖理
Gary?
奥利维亚
Olivia.
上次之后  我没想到你还会来
After last time, I-I didn't think that you would come.
我本来没打算来  但是...
I wasn't going to, but...
我很高兴你来了
I'm glad you did.
我也是
So am I.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
什么
What?
怦怦跳动的声音
The thumping noise?
是你吗
Is -- is that you?
你能听见
You can hear that?
盖理
Gary!
盖理  是什么
Gary, what is it?! What --
盖理  盖理
Gary! Gary!
《凶鬼恶灵》第八季第七集
对  是的
Right, yeah.
不  只要你发现什么就立刻打给我们
No, just, uh -- just call us whenever you find something.
英勇的猎人
是的
Yeah.
对  当然
Yeah, course.
对  不是  我
Right. No, I-I, uh...
对  你知道吗  迪恩在我旁边
Yeah, hey, you know what? Uh, Dean's here.
他想和你说两句
He really wants to talk to you.
谭夫人  对  你好
Ms. Tran, yeah, hi, uh...
隧道
Tunnel.
谭家那边又怎么了
What's going on in Tran-land?
盖思最终把他们带去了他的船屋
Well, uh, Garth finally got them to his houseboat,
但是凯文要阅读他们的
but Kevin's having a lot of trouble
那半石碑是困难重重
reading their half of the tablet.
到目前为止  都是些零零碎碎的
So far, bits and pieces.
没有关于封闭地狱的内容
Nothing about boarding up hell.
盖思有艘安全船屋
Garth has a safe-houseboat?
老兄  我都不再问这些问题了
Dude, I don't even ask questions anymore.
小卡  有什么消息
What's the word, Cass?
[小卡以为问的是"小卡这个词是什么意思"]
是我昵称
It's a shortened version of my name.
没错  但我问的是道上有什么消息
Yes, it is. I meant what's the word on the word?
天使"无线电"里有没有关于石碑的消息
Any, uh, tablet chatter on angel radio?
说不准  我把那关了
Oh, I couldn't say. I turned that off.
-你可以关掉吗  -是的  只不过是
- You can do that? - Yeah, it's a simple matter
阻隔住特定的次音速频率
of blocking out certain subsonic frequencies.
如果你们想了解我可以画图表解释
I could draw you a diagram if you want.
不用  这样就行
No, that's -- we're good.
你为什么要关了
Why'd you flip the switch?
因为那能直接连接到天堂
Because it's a direct link to heaven.
我再也不想和那地方有所牵连
And I don't want anything to do with that place -- not anymore.
那现在要怎样
So what now?
搬去佛蒙特  开一家迷人的小旅馆吗
Move to Vermont, open up a charming B&B?
不要  我还想...我还得去帮助人类
No. I still want -- I still need to help people.
所以  我要做个猎人
So...I'm gonna become a hunter.
真的吗
Really?
真的  我可以做你们的电灯泡
Yeah. I could be your third wheel.
third wheel还有"累赘"的意思
你知道那不是件好事吧
You know that's not a good thing, right?
当然是  多一个人能多一份握力能更加稳定
Of course it is. A third wheel adds extra grip, greater stability.
我甚至都找好案子了
I even found a case.
俄克拉荷马市
Oklahoma city --
一男子心脏从胸膛中跳出十英尺
a man's heart jumped 10 feet out of his chest.
听起来是我们的案子  对吧
It sounds like our kind of thing, right?
-他说得对  -太好了  到那儿见
- He's got a point.  - Excellent. I'll see you there.
等等  小卡  小卡
Wait, Cass, Cass.
你想扮牛仔吸血鬼什么的  没问题
If you want to play cowboys and bloodsuckers, that's fine.
但是你要和我们在一起  好吗
But you're gonna stick with us, okay?
不要再做这种傻事  明白吗
None of this zapping around crap. Capiche?
好  我明白了
Yeah, I capiche.
那好吧
All right, then.
我能坐在副驾驶座上吗
Can I, uh, at least ride in the front seat?
不行  不行
No. No.
法医说他的心脏从身体里喷射出来
Coroner said his heart was ejected from his body.
呼吸新鲜空气  在沙盒里找到它了
Got some air, too. Found it in a sandbox.
探长  你有何看法
Any idea what happened, detective?
纳什探员  许多人都认为是吸毒
A lot of people are thinking drugs, agent Nash --
吸毒过量
An assload of drugs.
男人体内没有毒品
There are no narcotics in that man's system.
他的分子都错乱了
His molecules are all wrong.
但是你不那么认为对吧
But you don't think that, huh?
从来没见过8号黑球能这样
Never seen an eightball do that.
是谁报的案
And who called this in?
他的朋友奥利维亚・库珀  她目睹了整件事
Friend of his named Olivia Kopple. She saw the whole thing.
该死  我得...我得接个电话
Ah, crap. I have -- I have to take this.
这里是我们所有线索  请自便  谢了
Here's everything we got. Knock yourself out. Thanks.
听着  如果你发现什么奇怪的
Listen, you see anything weird,
任何不同寻常的事  打给我
anything out of the box, you just call me.
斯科林  你说了算
Whatever you say, Scully.
格拉斯探长  立刻去
Detective Glass. On my way.
我感觉不到任何电磁干扰或硫磺
I can't sense any EMF or sulfur.
弗里林先生的动脉很健康
Mr. Frieling's arterial health is, uh, excellent.
他近期患有轻度的
He did recently suffer from a...mild, uh...
什么来着  膀胱感染
what is that? Bladder infection.
小卡  别再闻死人了
Cass, stop smelling the dead guy.
为什么  现在我了解这男人的一切
Why? Now I know everything about this man.
我们就可以
So we can --
你知道他有外遇吗
Do you know he was having an affair?
什么
What?
神探夏洛克  得一分
Strike one, Sherlock.
据奥利维亚说
According to Olivia,
他们每周四12点45分都会在公园见面
they would meet at the park every Thursday at 12:45,
走去月光餐厅
walk to the Moonlight Diner,
她总会点一份凯撒沙拉
where she always ordered a Caesar salad,
沙拉酱放在旁边
dressing on the side.
他们会一起聊天
They would chat about everything,
1点30分她会回去
and she'd be back on the road by 1:30.
你觉得她说谎了
You don't think she's telling the truth.
太多细节了  听起来像是事先排练过
Too much detail. Sounds rehearsed.
还有  我们进城的路上
Plus, we drove past the Moonlight Diner
经过月光餐厅
on the way into town.
紧靠着月光汽车旅馆
It's attached to the Moonlight Motel.
好吧  假设这位盖理有外遇
Okay, well, let's say that, uh, Gary here's on the prowl,
但是他又谨慎行事因为...
but he's playing it safe because...
他结婚了
...dude's married.
不想被别人看到他的车停在
Doesn't want anyone to see his ride parked out
按小时收费的廉价旅馆门口
in front of a by-the-hour fleabag.
所以他就把车藏在街对面的公园里
So he stashes his car at the park across the street,
在那里见奥利维亚
Meets Olivia there.
他的妻子可能发现了
His wife probably found out about it,
让她心碎  所以她也弄碎了他的心
and it broke her heart. So she breaks his.
听着像是巫师一类的
Sounds witchy.
的确
Yes, it does.
这家伙暗地里玩私情
Guy was living a lie,
终于给私情玩死了
and it came back to bite him in the ticker.
能诊断出膀胱感染也挺厉害的
But nice job on the bladder infection.
艾米利亚与唐白头偕老
他说五点之前到
He said he'd be here by 5:00.
深呼吸
Uh, just deep breath.
-不会有事的  -我知道
- It's gonna be okay. - I know.
只是新房子  还有你
It's just this house, you --
他会认为我们进展太快
He's gonna think we're moving too fast.
我们有没有进展太快
Are we moving too fast?
我们是在弥补错过的时光
We're making up for lost time.
别谈政治
Don't talk politics.
别说牛仔的坏话
Don't say anything bad about the cowboys.
而且无论你做什么
And whatever you do, don't --
千万别用"潮湿"和"不管"这两个词
do not use the words "moist" or "irregardless."
我的开场白是作废了
There goes my opener.
你好  爸爸
Hi, dad!
我的小家伙
Ohh, munchkin!
好了  怪丢人的
Okay, embarrassing.
那是我的工作  孩子
That is my job, kiddo.
这小帅哥是谁呀
So, who's this handsome fella?
他可是个好小伙
Yeah, he's a good boy!
你怎么样啊  真帅气
How you doing there? You're beautiful.
那只好小伙是这位好小伙的
That good boy belongs to this good boy.
斯坦・汤普森  这是萨姆・温彻斯特
Stan Thompson, this is Sam Winchester.
-你好  -多有耳闻
- Hi. - I heard a lot about you.
希望不都是坏话
Not all bad, I hope.
地方不错  草坪该剪了
So, this is a nice place. Lawn could use a mow.
萨姆找的
Sam found it.
我最近实在是忙
I've been so busy lately.
他差不多是一个人给我们搬的家
He's had to move us in by himself, pretty much.
也算做得不错
Job almost well done.
爸  要饮料吗  我们有啤酒  冰茶
Do you want a drink, dad? We have beer, iced tea --
只要是凉的就好  谢谢亲爱的
Anything cold will be fantastic. Thank you, sweetheart.
好
Okay.
汤普森先生
Mr. Thompson, um, I just --
我知道事情很尴尬
I know this must be weird.
你几个月没见艾米利亚
Uh, you haven't seen Amelia in months,
她又跟一个你不认识的人住在一起
and now she's living with a guy you've never met.
艾米说你读过斯坦福
Ame said you went to Stanford.
是的
I did.
-是所好学校  -的确
- It's a good school. - It is.
你现在做什么
So what do you do now?
在镇上一家旅馆工作
I work at a motel in town.
做账吗
Balancing the books?
不  主要做维修
Uh, no. Maintenance mostly.
这就说得通了
Well, that makes sense.
我必须承认  萨姆
'cause I got to say, Sam,
我看你十分欠修理
You look like a real fixer-upper to me.
我不明白
I-I don't understand.
盖理死于心脏病发作
Gary had a heart attack.
联调局怎么会...
Why would the FBI --
公园是国家财产
The parks are government property.
我们只问你几个问题
We just got a few questions for you.
我来处理
I'll, uh... I'll handle this.
我做过研究  我能撬开她的嘴
I've done research. I can crack her.
弗里林夫人
Now, Ms. Frieling,
我不想给你添麻烦  真的
I don't want to bother you. I-I really don't.
可是我有一个问题要问你
But I-I do have just one question for you.
你为什么要杀你丈夫
Why did you kill your husband?!
斯蒂尔探员  借一步说话
Agent Stills. A word, please.
干什么  我在扮黑脸
What? I was being bad cop.
不  你扮的是四不像
No, you were being bad everything.
抱歉  原谅我搭档
Please, forgive my partner.
他最近有些心事
He's, uh -- he's going through some stuff.
学学萨姆
Listen to Sam.
他想问的是  有没有可能
What he was trying to ask -- is -- is there any way
盖理有一些秘密
Gary might have had secrets --
隐瞒着你
something he was hiding?
隐瞒  隐瞒什么
Hiding? Like what?
黛比
Deb?
奥利维亚
Olivia.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
就是那个情妇奥利维亚
As in mistress Olivia?
尴尬了
This is awkward.
抱歉  你们说盖理隐瞒了什么
I'm sorry. W-what did you think Gary was hiding?
他跟她有一腿
That he was sleeping with her.
我知道
I know.
你知道
You know?
盖理和我
Gary and I --
我们有个约定
we... had an arrangement.
他可以同奥利维亚约会
He was seeing olivia,
我有时候跟邻居PJ在一起
and I was spending some time with our neighbor P.J.
我去把这个放到厨房
I'll, uh -- I'll put this in the kitchen.
-我去帮你  -好
- I'll help. Okay. - Yeah.
疯狂的郊区
Frigging suburbs, man.
这么说她不是女巫
So she's not a witch.
世上最好的老婆
Just the best wife ever.
-那是什么杀了她丈夫  -谁管...
- Then what killed her husband? - Who gives a...
这是奇迹
It's a miracle!
上帝要我活下去
God wants me to live!
像是自杀
Loks like suicide.
就是自杀  留了遗书
It was. Guy left a note.
他白手起家建了罗马工业
He invested everything in Roman Industries
又在去年赔了个一干二净
and lost it all when they crashed and burned last year.
那为什么找我们
So why call us?
因为有两名目击者坚称
Because I have two witnesses who swear
他们看到马多夫在空中停了有10秒
that Madoff here floated in midair for a good 10 seconds,
然后向下一看  才摔下去
then he looked down, and splat.
我不确定是不是相信  但是听他们讲来
Not sure I buy that, but the way they're talking,
-简直就像是  -卡通片
- It sounds like something straight out of a... - Cartoon.
探长
Hey, detective.
-你们说在查怪事  -多谢
- You said you wanted weird. - Thanks.
-有什么发现  -她说的对
- Yeah, what do you got? - She's right, you know.
你看  心从胸膛里跳出来
I mean, the whole heart jumping out of the guy's chest,
坠落延迟
the -- the -- the delayed fall --
完全就是兔八哥
That's straight-up Bugs Bunny.
Bugs直译昆虫 Bunny直译兔子 小卡不知道兔八哥
那么我要找的是一只兔虫合体怪
So we're looking for some sort of insect-rabbit hybrid?
怎么杀掉它
How do we kill it?
杀不掉的  小卡
No, we don't, Cass.
那是个动画角色
That's a character, like, uh --
就像啄木鸟伍迪和达菲鸭
like Woody Woodpecker or Daffy Duck.
是动画短片
They're little animated movies.
歪心狼追着哔哔鸟
You know, uh, the Coyote chases a roadrunner,
铁砧从天而降砸在他头上
and then the -- the anvil gets dropped on his head.
这很好笑吗
Is it supposed to be funny?
不
No.
是滑稽
It's hilarious.
不要走开  孩子们  我们马上回来
Stay tuned, kids! We'll be right back!
我懂了
I understand.
哔哔鸟代表上帝
The bird represents god.
歪心狼就是人类  一刻不停地追索神意
And Coyote is man, endlessly chasing the divine,
却从来求之不得
yet never able to catch him. It's...
很滑稽
It's hilarious.
完全不知道我们要对付的是什么
I got no idea what we're hunting.
也许是个念相
Maybe it's a tulpa.
念相: 通过形象化技巧想象出的状态或物体
也许是某个《机械鸡》
Maybe it's some...some crazy god
《机械鸡》是2005年上映的美国电视连续剧
看多了的疯狂的神
who watched too much "Robot Chicken."
我是说
I-I...I mean, is there a link
这两起事件之间有联系吗
between "Heartbreak hotel" And "Free falling"?
我是找不到
Not that I can find.
好吧  我要休息一会
All right, well, I'm gonna call it.
小卡  你要定个房间吗
Cass, you gonna book a room or what?
不  我留在这里
No, I'll stay here.
好吧
Oh, okay. Yeah.
我们开个睡衣派对然后帮萨姆编辫子
We'll have a slumber party and braid Sam's hair.
你要睡在哪
Where are you gonna sleep?
我不睡觉
I don't sleep.
好吧  我需要睡四个小时
Okay, well, I need my four hours, so...
我会看守着你的
I'll watch over you.
这可不行
That's not gonna happen.
警察局发生了一些事
Something's coming across the police band.
你能听见
Wait, you can hear that?
都是无线电波
It's all waves.
一家银行被抢劫了  听起来很疯狂
A bank has been robbed. It sounds loony.
什么叫疯狂
Define "Loony."
好吧  这就叫疯狂
That's loony, all right.
特工们  我正要打电话给你们
Agents. I was just about to give you a ring.
我得问句  是你们追着疯狂的事件呢
Got to ask...do you boys chase the crazy,
还是疯狂的事专发生在你们身边
or does the crazy chase you?
要看当天状况了
Depends on the day.
-这是谁被压成肉饼了  -保安
- Who's the pancake? - Security guard.
他报案有抢劫
He called in reporting a robbery,
-但当我们赶来时  -抢劫
- but by the time we got here... - A robbery?
当这个黑洞正在试图
Looks like the Black Hole was trying to
撬开保险箱时
jimmy open a safe-deposit box
这位业余警察发现了他
when Mr. Rent-a-cop found him.
然后  你们也知道事情的结局
And, well, you know how that story ends.
黑洞
Black Hole?
那是我们对把我们耍得团团转的窃贼的称呼
It's our name for a burglar that's been running us ragged.
他很专业  没留下任何指纹
He's a pro...no fingerprints,
没有任何强行闯入的迹象
never any sign of forced entry...
每次只留下一双那东西  就像他留下的签名
Just a pair of those every time, like he's signing his work.
尽管明显  罪犯从没做过这样的事
Perp's never done anything like this before, though...obviously.
你介意我看一下其他
You mind if I take a look at your files
类似入室抢劫的资料吗
on those other break-ins?
没问题
No skin off my nose.
我现在要去警局  若你愿意可以搭顺风车
I'm headed to the station now if you want a ride.
太好了
Perfect.
你能抬起来它吗
Hey. Can you lift this?
用X做标记
"X" marks the spot.
无论是谁  都是按照动画片中的规则
Well, whoever's doing this is playing by cartoon rules.
-动画片里没有规则  -当然有
- Animation doesn't have rules. - Sure it does.
在卡通片里  一个美女
In toontown, a pretty girl
可以让你的心赃跳出胸口
can make your heart leap out of your chest,
铁砧从天而降
anvils fall from the sky.
而且如果你在墙上画个门或洞
And if you draw a door or a black hole on the wall,
你就可以穿墙而过
you can stroll right through it.
窃贼就是这样进来的
So this is how the thief got in.
也是这样出去和破开地下室的
And out, and cracked the vault.
那为什么现在不管用了
Then why isn't it working now?
我也不知道
I got no clue.
你父亲
Your father...
字写得很漂亮
Beautiful handwriting.
你感觉怎么样  小卡
How you feeling, cass?
我很好
I'm fine.
我是说  我知道当我
Well, I just...I-I know that when...
从炼狱逃出来后
I got puked out of purgatory,
我用了好几周才适应过来
it took me a few weeks to... find my sea legs.
我感觉很好
I'm fine.
不要想偏了  我很高兴你能回来
Don't get me wrong. I'm happy you're back.
我快激动死了
I'm freaking thrilled.
只是神奇复活这事...
It's just this whole mysterious-resurrection thing...
总是会有不好的副作用
It always has one mother of a downside.
那你想让我怎样
So, what do you want me to do?
你也许可以上去一次
Maybe take a trip upstairs.
去天堂
To heaven?
是的  四处逛一逛
Yeah, poke around,
看看上帝使团知不知道你是怎么出来的
see if the God squad can't tell us how you got out.
不行
No.
我和你一样烦那些
Look, man, I-I hate those flying-ass monkeys
飞来飞去的事
just as much as you do, but...
迪恩  我说了不行
Dean! I said no!
和我谈谈
Talk to me.
迪恩  我
Dean, I...
当我变坏的时候
When I was...bad...
那些不好的东西
and I had all those things...
那些利维坦  在我体内翻滚
The...the leviathans... writhing inside me...
我给世间制造了太多苦难
I caused a lot of suffering on earth,
但是我毁灭了天堂
but I devastated heaven.
我杀害了成千上万的同胞
I vaporized thousands of my own kind,
我不能回去
and I-I-I can't go back.
因为如果你回去  天使们会杀了你
Cause if you do, the angels will kill you.
是因为我看清了天堂的模样
Because if I see what heaven's become...what I...
我把它变成的模样  我害怕我会自杀
...what I made of it... I'm afraid I might kill myself.
有线索了
Hey. Got something.
很好  是什么线索
Good. Excellent. What?
这位黑洞  在他抢劫银行前
So this black-hole guy...before he tried the bank,
他抢劫了盖理猝死的那个
he robbed a house across from the park
公园对面的一座房子
where Gary blew a gasket.
那么你觉得那入室抢劫
So, uh, you think the house heist
与盖理的死亡之间有联系
and Gary's corpse are connected?
根据资料记录
According to the file,
这两件事恰好同时发生
they happened at pretty much the exact same time.
来看看这个
Here. Check this out. Okay.
这是那座房子  盖理死在街对面的这里
Here's the house, and Gary died across the street here.
还有今早我们去的那个楼在这
And that building from this morning...right there.
黑洞也抢劫了那
The black hole hit that, too.
让我猜猜  不管是谁来了次燕式跳水
Let me guess...where, uh, what's his name took a swan dive.
好吧  我相信  那其他的呢
All right. I'll bite. What about the others?
那些是被偷窃的地方
Well, those are the places that stuff got stolen.
但是没有人死亡
But nobody got dead.
除了那些涂鸦
Take away the graffiti,
这一切都看起来像是普通的砸窗抢劫事件
and these all look like just normal smash-and-grabs.
但我打了几通电话
But I made a few phone calls,
和当时在场的以及附近居住的人交谈了一番
talked to some people who are nearby...neighbors and whatnot.
他们说了一大番难以置信的话
And they reported a whole lot of crazy.
比如
Like?
比如一个慢跑的人碰烂了头
Like a jogger bumping his head
长出了四英尺大的肿块
and sprouting a four-inch lump.
再比如一个孩子走到了墙里听见了鸟叫
Or a kid walking into a wall and hearing birdies.
基本上  每处抢劫点周围50码内
Basically, for 50 yards around each robbery,
人们就像生活在卡通片里
people were living in a cartoon.
但持续时间都不长
But it didn't last long.
每处都是大概持续5至10分钟
I mean, 5, 10 minutes at each place.
这种时间长度足够窃贼进去再出来
About the length of time it would take a thief to get in and out.
没错
Exactly.
无论他用的是什么力量  都不是单个锁定的
But whatever power he's using it's...it's not targeted.
我是说它会影响一片区域
I mean, it's...it's kind of like an area of effect.
他就像是在一个奇怪的气泡中
I mean, picture him in a bubble of weird,
一切碰到它的东西都会变得疯狂
and anything that touches it gets daffy.
也就是说这个卡通家伙可以穿墙
So this animaniac can step through walls,
投掷铁砧
can toss an anvil?
是的  但他是在扭曲事实的基础上做到的
Yeah, but he's warping reality to do it.
所以某人恰好在
So if someone happens to be nearby
他梦中女孩旁边的话
meeting the girl of his dreams...
他的心脏就会迸出来
His heart makes a break for it.
好吧  那么砸碎橱窗  保安
Okay, so smashing the, uh -- the rent-a-cop --
那是故意的  但其余的
That -- that was on purpose, but the rest of them --
诡异事件只是巧合吗
What, is that just collateral weird?
也许
Maybe.
那么我们是在找一个窃贼
So we're looking for a thief.
还有他偷去的存款箱
And the deposit box he was after.
现在  那间屋子  那间办公室
Now, the house, the office --
他去过的每个地方
every place he's hit
都属于住在日落之家养老院的某个人
belonged to someone living at the sunset fields retirement home.
所以你认为我们应该去那里
So you think our guy's there.
值得一试
Worth a shot.
好吧  我们整装待发  现在是猎兔时节
All right. Well, let's gear up. It's wabbit season.
我想那个词你发错音了
I don't think you pronounced that correctly.
得了  没那么严重吧
Come on. It's not that bad.
你不会告诉我这个呼吸机
You can't tell me this joint
不会让你浑身不自在
doesn't give you the heebs and/or jeebs.
-你好  有事吗  -你好
- Hello. Can I help you? - Hi.
克罗斯比探员  联调局的
Yeah. Agent crosby. FBI.
抱歉  我是德怀特・马霍尼医生
Sorry, I'm Dr. Dwight Mahoney.
我经营日落之家
I run sunset fields.
我们需要问询你的病人
We need to question your residents.
为什么  关于什么
Well...why? About what?
主要是关于盗窃案
Grand larceny, mostly.
当然  请随便问
Of course. Um, by all means, ask away.
如果有事需要帮忙  请通知我
If there's anything I can do to help, let me know.
谢谢  太好了
Appreciate it. Great.
好吧  我们办正事  你们俩不要调情
All right, let's do this. No flirting, you two.
你真是太帅了  查尔斯
You are so pretty, Charles.
那不是我的名字
That's not my name.
你太像我的第三任丈夫了
Oh! You look so much like my third husband.
夫人  我们来此是为了调查盗窃案
We're here to talk about the robbery, ma'am.
-盗窃案  -是的
- Robbery? - Mm-hmm.
几天前警察找你谈过此案
The one the police talked to you about a few days ago.
有人闯进你的老房子
Someone broke into your old house
还偷走了一摞无记名债券
and stole a stack of bearer bonds
和你藏在地板下的一些首饰
and, uh, some jewelry that you stashed under your floorboards.
没错  是我的钻石  我把它们藏在那
Oh, my diamonds, yes. I hid them there.
对不起  查尔斯
I'm sorry, Charles.
我信不过你
I didn't trust you.
你可是个无赖之徒
You were quite the bounder.
你告诉过任何人贵重物品的藏身之处吗
Did you tell anyone where your valuables were,
塔特夫人
Mrs. Tate?
我想没有
I don't think so.
不过有时我有些糊涂
But then I get a little fuzzy sometimes.
你最近有注意到什么奇怪的事情
Have you noticed anything strange lately --
气温骤冷  气味
Uh, cold spots, smells?
那儿有只猫
Well, there's the cat.
一只猫
The cat?
它有时会说话
He talks sometimes.
对老鼠可是恨之入骨
Really hates that mouse.
我去审讯那只猫
I'll interrogate the cat.
你吃完了吗
You all done here?
好的
All right.
很诡异  是吧
It's creepy, right?
很多老人
A lot of these people --
他们对外界充耳不闻  只活在自己的世界里
They just tune out and live in their own heads.
就好像现实世界过于复杂  他们无法承受
It's like maybe the real world is too much for them,
他们只能逃避  你明白吗
and they just run and hide, you know?
汤好了  还有咸味酱
Soup's on... and semi-edible.
你还记得
You remembered.
爸爸曾在军队服役
Dad was in the army,
所以小时候我们经常搬家
so we moved around a lot when I was a kid.
吃意大利面条和热狗是我们搬进新家
Having spaghetti and hot dogs our first night in a new house
-第一晚的传统  -明白了
- was sort of a tradition. - All right. Got it.
我爸爸曾在海军陆战队服役
Uh, my father was in the marines.
锅盖头[对海军陆战队士兵的谐称]
Jarhead, huh?
没错  第一海军陆战队二营回音兵团
That's right. Uh, 2nd battalion, first marines, echo company.
我一直以为他们有些趾高气扬
I always thought they were a little puffed up, myself.
但是  我知道什么
But, hey. What do I know?
我只不是一个老步兵
I'm just an old grunt.
你是我的老步兵
You're my old grunt.
艾米告诉我你没有参过军
So, Ame tells me you never served.
没有
No.
看  我很难相信
See, I find that hard to believe
因为我不得不说  萨姆
'cause I got to say, Sam,
你有那种神色
you got the look.
神色
The look?
很多人在历经了
The one a lot of guys get after
战场的血腥后的神色
they've been through the meat grinder --
那种神色能让你知道
The one that let's you know
他们见识过许多难以忘怀的场面
they've seen a lot of crap they can't forget.
一旦他们的脚踏上土地
The second their feet hit solid ground,
他们开始奔跑  并且不会停止
they start running, and they don't stop --
直到他们找到可以依靠的东西
Not till they find something to hold on to.
你认为我是这样的人
You think that's what I'm doing here?
只是找个依靠
Just holding on?
我认为你们彼此互相依靠
I think the two of you are holding on to each other, yeah.
因为我知道她很害怕
'Cause I know she's scared.
唐牺牲后  我没有责备她离我而去
After what happened to Don, I don't blame her for taking off.
我知道她为什么要逃避现实
Needing to run away and hide -- I know why she did it.
问题是  萨姆  你在逃避什么
The question is -- what are you running from, Sam?
你有收获吗
Hey, what do you got?
没有  没有魔法袋  没有电磁干扰  你呢
Hey, um, nothing. Uh, no hex bags, no EMF. You?
一无所获
Nada.
一半我问过的人都不记得被抢劫了
Half the folks I talked to don't even remember being robbed.
迪恩
Dean, um...
你记得一个叫弗雷德・琼斯的人吗
You remember a guy named Fred Jones?
我觉得他和爸爸有联系  他住在盐湖外面
I think he was a contact of dad's, lived outside of salt lake.
记得  我的第一瓶啤酒就是他给的
Yeah, that guy gave me my first beer.
我觉得那是我还没满十岁呢
I don't even think I was double digits.
没错  我也是  他是个通灵师  对吧
Right, yeah. Me, too. Um, he was psychic, right?
心灵致动师  问这个干吗
Psychokinetic. Why?
因为他就在114号房间
'Cause he's in room 114.
小卡  我们走
Cass. Let's go.
我差点让它奔溃
I've almost cracked him.
现在就走
Now.
我和你还没完
Hey. I'm not through with you.
笨蛋
Dumbass.
琼斯先生
Mr. Jones?
你好  我是 萨姆・温彻斯特
Hey, it's, uh, Sam Winchester.
弗雷德
Fred?
我太紧张了  快叫医生
My nerves! Get me a doctor!
弗雷德  嘿
Fred! Hey!
那么  你真的认为这个人
So, you really think this one man
就是这几起惨案的罪魁祸首
is causing all of these... shenanigans?
如果是他
Well, if he is,
他周围肯定会有蹊跷  对吧
he'd be surrounded by a circle of crazy, right?
等等
Hang on.
猜对了
Bingo.
怎么回事
But how?
弗雷德与众不同
Fred's got juice.
我是说一般的心灵致动师能用意念移动物体
I mean, an average psychokinetic can move things with his mind,
但是像弗雷德
But a guy like Fred --
你要是激怒他  他就能改写现实
you get him worked up, He can reshape reality.
好吧  但是如何屏蔽他的超能力
All right, so where's his "Off" Switch?
我不知道
I don't know.
我甚至都不确定他是否知道我们在这里
I'm not even certain if he knows we're here.
我们要杀了他吗
Do we...kill him?
打扰  探员
Excuse me, agents.
他刚才是不是威胁要谋杀我的病人
Did he just threaten to murder one of my patients?
顺利到让人感到诡异
Real freaking smooth.
我们不必丢下他不管
Well, we don't have to leave him.
我能瞬间移动他
I could teleport him.
弗雷德能影响到周边  小卡
Fred's radioactive, Cass.
直接挪走他  谁知道会出什么事
Zap him -- no telling what will happen.
今晚我和萨姆会杀个回马枪
Me and Sam will circle back tonight,
干净利落地接走弗雷德
Get Fred nice and clean.
你悄悄行事看着他一点  听见了吗
You go invisible girl and keep an eye on him. You hear me?
很好
Good.
生日快乐  希拉
Happy birthday, Sheila.
好极了
Ha. Good.
准备好  猛吸一口气
Get ready. Big breath.
准备好了
Oh, ready.
我来擦干净你的脸  好吗
I'm just gonna wipe this off your face, okay?
我要给你戴上这个
I'm just gonna put this on.
你收到我的信息了  很好
Oh. You got my message. Good.
到底出了什么事
What the hell happened?
是蛋糕出了不幸
There was a pastry mishap.
好吧  然后呢
Okay, and?
然后那些霜糖喷溅的速度接近超音速
And the frosting reached near-supersonic speeds.
我以为
I thought --
弗雷德不见了
Hey. Fred's gone. Hey.
什么  真他妈的好
What? Oh, fan-freaking-tastic.
真该挖了你的眼睛
Way to take your eye off the ball.
你们不该来这儿的
You're not supposed to be here.
相信我亲爱的  你还有更要紧的事
Well, trust me, sweetheart, you got bigger fish.
查尔斯  她戴着我的钻石
Charles, she's wearing my diamonds.
等一下
Wait.
怎么了  有什么不对吗
What? What's wrong?
这是塔特夫人的手链
This is Mrs. Tate's bracelet.
你从哪儿弄来的
Where did you get it?
回答问题
Answer the question.
我男朋友给我的
My boyfriend gave it to me.
看  不记名债券
Hey. Bearer bonds.
也许这些都是希拉・塔特的
Maybe these belonged to Sheila Tate.
这家伙就是我们要找的贼了
So this man is our thief.
是的  迪恩
Yeah. Dean.
小卡
Cass.
待着别动
Stay still.
拿开你的手
Move your hands.
你是怎么
How did you...
-他自有办法  萨姆来帮一把  -你怎么
- Guy eats his wheaties. Sam, come on. - What did you...
起来  坐好
Get up. Come on. Sit down.
等等  你们刚刚把我怎么样了
Wait a second! What did you just do to me?!
听我说  弗雷德・琼斯在哪儿
Hey, hey, hey! Listen to me. Where is Fred Jones?
我  是他把他带走了
I -- he -- he took him.
谁
Who?!
马霍尼医生  那家伙就是个魔鬼懂吗
Dr. Mahoney. That guy's evil, man, okay?
-他在利用琼斯先生  -怎么利用
- He's using Mr. Jones  - How?
弗雷德只是看看卡通  但他太不可思议了
Look, all Fred does is watch cartoons, but he is magic, okay?
几个星期前  我的脚撞上了他的门
A few weeks ago, I-I slammed my foot in his door.
我把门撞扁了  我意思是真扁了
I smashed it flat -- and I mean flat.
后来我晃了晃门  它就恢复了原状
And then when I shook the thing, it popped back up,
就像是从卡通片里出来似的
Like something out of a cartoon or whatever.
对对  我们知道
Yeah, yeah, yeah, we know.
然后我就告诉了马霍尼医生  他开始了实验
So I told dr. Mahoney, and then he started doing experiments.
我们只想看看他能做些什么
Just -- we just wanted to see what he could do.
那些盗窃案呢
What about the robberies?
马霍尼已经在日落之家捞了好些年
Oh, Mahoney's been skimming off Sunset Fields for years.
这些老人中有不少都藏了些东西
A lot of those folks -- they got stuff stashed away,
就是没有登记的那些
like, off the books.
所以马霍尼会去找那些财物
So Mahoney would track down the loot,
我们也会带弗雷德一起出去兜兜风
and then we would take Fred for a drive.
没错  再用他那些诡异的招数偷窃
Right, and use his bubble of weird to rip people off.
你怎么搞到中枪了
How did you end up gut-shot?
马霍尼  他碾碎了那个保安之后
Mahoney -- after -- after he anviled that guard,
他有点害怕了  你们也出现了
he started freaking out, and then you showed up,
蛋糕又在休息室里爆开了花  然后他失控了
and then the cake blew in the day room, and then he lost it.
你说"他失控了"是什么意思
What does that mean, "He lost it"?
我是说他现在正在去银行的路上
I mean he's on his way back to
想最后一搏
the bank right now for one last score.
医生到处为非作歹
Doc's blowing town.
我是说  他说弗雷德是个累赘
I mean, he said that Fred was a loose end.
他打算杀了他
He was gonna kill him.
可我喜欢弗雷德
And then I like Fred,
我就说如果你要伤害他  我就报警
so I said that if he hurt the guy, I'd go to the cops.
我不知道他有枪
And I didn't know that he had a gun.
明白了
Okay.
你觉得琼斯先生知道发生了什么事吗
Do you think Mr. Jones knows what's happening?
我不清楚
I don't know.
我觉得这个老伙计就好像活在梦境之中
Seems to me like the dude's living in a dream world.
听着  我是想帮忙的
Look, I am trying to help.
孩子  我跟你说  如果唐能看见你
Boy, I'll tell you, if Don could see you...
别  别说了
Don't. Just don't.
你不能  你该回家
You can't -- you need to come home.
你来就是为了这个  为了劝我回去
Is that why you're here -- to drag me back?
这是我的生活
This is my life.
这种生活  不会长久
This -- it won't last.
你这是活在梦境之中
You are living in a dream world.
我喜欢这地方  我喜欢这房子
I like it here. I like this house.
我喜欢萨姆
I like Sam.
萨姆简直一团糟
Sam is a mess.
我也是
I'm a mess.
可我和萨姆在一起的时候我很开心  爸爸
But when I'm with Sam, I'm happy, Dad.
我已经很久没这么开心了
And I haven't been happy in a really long time.
所以  就让我们两个同病相怜吧
So please, just... let us be messes together.
给我们一个机会
Give us a chance.
我来擦干
I'll dry.
外面是你的车吗  那辆英帕拉
Is that your car outside -- the Impala?
对  以前是我爸的车
Yeah, it was my Dad's.
你爸好品味
Guy had good taste...
对一个当兵的来说
...for a jarhead.
好吧  琼斯肯定就在附近
All right. Jones has got to be close.
我去银行看看  你们看看能不能找到他
I'll hit the bank. You see if you can find him.
太棒了
Awesome.
你感觉到了吗  萨姆
Can you feel that, Sam?
那股力量
The power.
你的女侠简恩
Calamity Jane for you!
弗雷德  喂  弗雷德  老伙计
Fred, hey. Fred, hey, buddy.
弗雷德  听我说
Hey. Hey, Fred? Listen to me.
你听得到我说话吗  弗雷德
Can you hear me? Fred!
我们能跟他说上话就好了
If we could just talk to him.
老伙计
Hey, buddy.
醒醒  醒醒啊
Hey, wake up. Wake up.
小卡
Cass?
等等
Wait. Wait!
小卡  我们这是在哪儿
Cass, uh, where are we?
在琼斯先生的脑海里
Inside Mr. Jones' mind.
你说想跟他说话的
You said you wanted to talk to him.
你们俩是谁
Who the hell are you?
弗雷德  弗雷德  是我
Fred. Fred. Um, hey, it's -- it's -- it's me.
我是萨姆・温彻斯特
I'm, uh -- I'm sam -- Sam Winchester.
约翰的儿子
John's boy?
没错
That's right.
骨瘦如柴的那个
The scrawny one?
我不见你才三四年吧
It's only been three, four years since I've seen you.
是差不多二十年
You -- more like, uh, 20.
听着弗雷德  我要你集中精神
Listen, Fred, I'm gonna need you to focus.
你是怎么
How did you...
你来这干吗  萨姆
Why are you here, Sam?
怎么了  医生
What's up, doc?
不不  你们在撒谎
No, no, no, no, no, no. You're lying!
这是事实  琼斯先生
This is happening, Mr. Jones.
他们在利用你
They're using you.
把我当什么  变态人体电池么
As what-- some kind of a damn psychic coppertop?
把我插上  然后全世界都乱套了
You plug me in, and the whole world goes wacky?
-不是这样的  -你怎么知道不是
- It doesn't work that way. - How would you know?
无意冒犯  但在我看来
No offense, but it seems to me
好像你在这里的时间
like you've been spending more time in here
比在外面还长
than you have... out there.
你想知道拥有这样头脑的我
You want to know what's the worst thing that can happen
最怕发生什么事吗
to a guy who's got a mind like I got?
就是失去这个头脑
Losing it.
你放我走  这东西一半都归你
You let me walk, and half of this is yours.
我还是算了吧
I think I'm gonna pass.
我还真不太喜欢偷老太太们的东西
I'm not really into stealing from sweet old ladies.
我不是从她们那里偷
I'm not stealing from them.
我偷的是她们孩子的东西
I'm stealing from their children.
小混蛋们觉得他们可以把家人
Little bastards think they can drop their folks off at a home
放在养老院  然后每年来看两次
and visit twice a year, maybe.
我照顾这些老家伙们
I took care of all these old geezers.
-我有资格  -我不关心
- I think I des-- - I don't care!
好吧
Fine.
听你的
Have it your way.
欢迎来到游乐园
Welcome to the fun house.
卡通片  我小时候就喜欢
Cartoons-- yeah, yeah, I always loved them when I was a kid.
它们令我感到开心和安全
They made me feel... happy-- safe.
它们是
They were...
可以依赖的东西
Something to hold on to.
是的
Yeah.
迪恩・温彻斯特
英勇的猎人
马霍尼医生
邪恶的怪人
放弃了吗
Give up?
几个月来  我一直活在这种疯狂中
I've been dealing with this crazy for months!
你这个白痴还带枪来打架
And you-- idiot -- bring a gun to a gag fight.
是啊  我是带了这个
Yeah, well, I did bring this.
那个叉可是个标记
And "X" marks the spot.
我需要你停止这些  控制住
I need you to stop this-- take control.
太难了
It's too hard!
听着  活在梦想的世界很好
Look, it can be nice living in a dream world.
那感觉非常棒  我知道
It can be great. I know that.
你可以躲起来
And you can hide,
还可以假装外界都不存在
and you can pretend all the crap out there doesn't exist,
但你不能永远这样  因为最终
but you can't do it forever because...eventually,
不论你在逃避什么  它都会找到你
whatever it is you're running from-- it'll find you.
它会找上门  给你致使一击
It'll come along, and it'll punch you in the gut.
然后
And then...
你必须醒过来  因为如果你不醒来
Then you got to wake up, because if you don't,
让梦一直这样下去的话  会毁了你的
then trying to keep that dream alive will destroy you!
会毁了一切的
It'll destroy everything!
貌似有人关掉了那蠢管道
Looks like somebody turned off the boob tube.
很好  那我就可以用这个了
Good. Means I can use this.
不
No!
不要再伤害任何人了
You are never going to hurt anyone again!
结束了  伙计们
That's all, folks.
天呐
My god.
弗雷德  你还好吗
Fred. You good?
现在我很好
Now I'm good.
一个月后  一年后
In a month, a year...
人越老会越不灵光
Nobody gets sharper with age.
我会再失控的
I'm gonna lose control again,
还会有人再受伤的
and somebody's gonna get hurt...again.
你得阻止
You got to make it stop.
可能有个办法
There might be a way.
过程可能很痛苦  而且结束的时候
The procedure will be painful, and...when it's over,
我不确定你还能有多少意识
I'm not sure how much of you will be left.
那你还等什么呢
Well, what are you waiting for?
他  他还好吗
Is he, uh -- is he okay?
他在听欢乐颂
He's listening to "Ode to Joy."
他很快乐
He's happy.
好吧  我们把这白蚁窝毁了吧
All right, well, let's blow this termite terrace.
卡斯  你可以坐前排了  干得好
Cass, you get to ride shotgun. You done good.
谢谢  可我
Thanks, but I, uh...
我不能去了  我
I can't come. I, uh...
你好啊  卡西迪奥
Hello, Castiel.
不行
And, no.
No?
我知道你在想什么  我不允许
I can see what you're thinking, and I won't allow it.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我一直努力假装
I have been trying to pretend
可以忘掉自己在天堂做的事  但我不能
that I can escape what I did in heaven, but I can't.
那些我所引起的伤痛
All that pain that I caused--
我得回来去纠正错误
I-I have to come back, to make things right.
你正在这样做  听令行事就对了
And you are... by doing what you're told.
底线是  除非我响铃
Bottom line-- unless I ring my bell,
否则别回天堂  卡西迪奥
you stay out of heaven, Castiel.
那我该做什么呢
Well, then, what should I do?
你想干什么呢
What do you want to do?
什么  小卡  为什么你不能一起走
You-- you what, Cass? W-why can't you come with us?
我
I, um...
我想和琼斯先生一起
I want to stay with Mr. Jones.
得有人照看他几天  保证他安全
Someone should watch over him for a few days just to be safe.
好的  之后呢
Okay, and then what?
我也不确定
Then I'm not sure.
但我知道我不能再逃了
But I know I can't run anymore.
艾米利亚扮演糖果仙子  是吧
So, Ame is playing the sugarplum fairy, right?
是吧
Right?
这是她的关键时刻  你懂的
Now, this is her big moment, you understand,
-她摇晃着走上台  -摇晃着吗
- And she waddles up onto the stage -- -Waddles?
怎么了  你那时是个胖丫头  很可爱
What? You were a chubby kid. It was adorable.
她摇晃着走上台
Anyway, she waddles up onto the stage,
背后还拖着两英尺的厕纸
and she is dragging two feet of toilet paper behind her.
不
No.
你记得吗
You remember that?
是啊
Yeah.
职业生涯的正式终结
Officially the end of her career.
-来一瓶吗  -好的  谢谢
- You want one of these? - Please, yeah.
谢谢
Thanks.
我哥哥以前就这样做
My, uh-- my brother used to do that.
-是吗  -是啊
- Yeah? - Yeah.
-他是个好人吗  -是的
- He a good guy? - Yeah.
是的  他是最棒的
Yeah, uh, he-- he was...the best.
我  我失去他了
Uh, I, uh... I lost him,
我跑掉了
and, uh, I-I ran.
真抱歉听到这个
I'm sorry to hear about that.
什么
What?
你确定吗
A-are you sure?
天呐
Oh, god.
艾米利亚
Amelia?
宝贝  你还好吗
Baby? You okay?
是唐
It's Don.
他还活着
He's alive.
萨姆  跟我走不
Sam, you with me?